<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/jekyll-theme-fitness/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/jekyll-theme-fitness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-27T01:35:31+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll-theme-fitness/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jekyll Theme - Fitness</title><subtitle>This is a beatiful style theme for jekyll.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The 10 Best Muscle-Building Foods</title><link href="/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/21/10-cheap-muscle-building-foods.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 10 Best Muscle-Building Foods" /><published>2018-11-21T12:16:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-21T12:16:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/21/10-cheap-muscle-building-foods</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/21/10-cheap-muscle-building-foods.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-10-best-muscle-building-foods&quot;&gt;The 10 Best Muscle-Building Foods&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-img&quot; src=&quot;/jekyll-theme-fitness/images/posts/The 10 Best Muscle-Building Foods/1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to build muscle, you need to lift weights AND eat enough calories to gain weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not all foods are made equal! With the wrong diet, it can be very easy to gain excess body fat along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below you’ll 10 cheap foods that are easy to prepare and great for gaining muscle. Plus, I’ve included some quick meal ideas for each food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-eggs&quot;&gt;1: EGGS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve heard it before: eggs are the perfect protein. Not only do they contain all the essential amino acids required for muscle growth, but the fat and cholesterol found in eggs are a key part of a testosterone-boosting diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are also extremely cheap and versatile – you can include them as part of your breakfast, lunch, or dinner. All of this makes them a staple of any muscle building diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Don’t worry about the “bad cholesterol” myth – the cholesterol found in eggs has actually been shown to decrease the amount of LDL (bad cholesterol) in your body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 QUICK MEAL IDEAS:
Bacon, eggs, and a bagel
Omelette (with veggies and meats)
Hard boiled eggs (convenient to take on-the-go)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-ground-beef&quot;&gt;2: GROUND BEEF&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know that meat is an amazing source of protein and calories — and this makes it ideal for packing on mass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, it’s full of iron. And iron deficiency has become quite common. If you experience this deficiency, your strength levels will drop (along with other bad symptoms), and this will ultimately prevent you from building muscle and making progress in the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have trouble gaining weight, I recommend getting the “80/20” variety because it packs more calories than a leaner cut like “90/10”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 QUICK MEAL IDEAS:
Ground beef scrambled with eggs and veggies
Ground beef mixed with instant brown rice and veggies
Ground beef hamburgers patties on buns&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-organic-milk&quot;&gt;3: ORGANIC MILK&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organic milk is a combination of pretty much everything you need to gain weight…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It contains a good source of both whey and casein protein (fast and slow release). Plus, if you stick with whole milk – and get the organic kind – it also contains more calories and more omega-3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do you want omega-3? It boosts cognitive function, lowers blood pressure, and even increases rates of muscle growth. For this reason, I also recommend taking a solid fish oil supplement daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 QUICK MEAL IDEAS:
Mixed with protein powder in a shake
Stirred in with oats, protein powder, and peanut butter
Chocolate milk (just add chocolate syrup)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-avocado&quot;&gt;4: AVOCADO&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If avocado is not part of your diet, you’re missing out bro. Not only is it stacked with healthy monounsaturated fatty acids, it’s also fucking delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An average avocado contains about 200 calories. Adding just one to your breakfast, lunch, or dinner is an easy way to pack in some extra calories… and make your meal taste WAY better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally prefer to mash it up with a fork and turn it into guacamole. This way, it’s easier to spread on a sandwich or mix in with some rice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 QUICK MEAL IDEAS:
Mashed up on a piece of toast with an egg
Mashed up and mixed in a bowl of rice with ground beef
Mashed up and spread on top of a sandwich or hamburger&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-quick-oats&quot;&gt;5: QUICK OATS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oats should be a go-to food for everyone who’s trying to gain weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, carbs need to be a large part of your diet if you want to optimize testosterone levels and supply your body with the energy it needs to get stronger and pack on mass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, oats are a “slow carb” which means you can eat a massive bowl of them and not have your insulin levels spike all over the place. When bulking up, your best bet is to eat your oats as part of your breakfast. This will maintain healthy blood sugar levels, control your appetite, and therefore help protect against extra fat gain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 QUICK MEAL IDEAS:
Blended with whole milk and protein powder
Oatmeal with whole milk and protein powder
Chocolate oatmeal breakfast cake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-instant-rice&quot;&gt;6: INSTANT RICE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rice is another slow-carb that’s easy to eat in large quantities, making it great for bulking up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will provide your body with the energy you need to get stronger and build mass. I recommend the instant variety, because you can just throw it in the microwave and it will be ready in 60 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, contrary to popular belief, brown rice is not necessarily superior to white rice. Sure, it has more fiber, but it also contains grains that can lead to an upset stomach if you eat a large quantity. Try both and decide which type you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 QUICK MEAL IDEAS:
Rice with ground beef and veggies
Rice with stir fried chicken and veggies
Rice mixed with beans&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The 10 Best Muscle-Building Foods</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Bulk up Fast</title><link href="/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/20/how-to-bulk-up-fast.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Bulk up Fast" /><published>2018-11-20T12:16:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-20T12:16:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/20/how-to-bulk-up-fast</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/20/how-to-bulk-up-fast.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-bulk-up-fast&quot;&gt;How to Bulk up Fast&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-img&quot; src=&quot;/jekyll-theme-fitness/images/posts/How to Bulk up Fast/1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bulking up and gaining muscle can be very challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes the right combination of diet and training to see fast results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, most guys never it right. And as a result, most guys fail to see significant progress. They usually stay scrawny or skinny-fat forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, I will give you 9 effective diet and workout tips for how to bulk up fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-keep-it-old-school&quot;&gt;1: Keep it old-school&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, “crossfit” style training has become very popular. For example, performing circuits or supersets where you rest very little in between sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These workouts are great for general health purposes and losing weight, but if you want to bulk up, then you need a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, you should do old-school workouts where you perform every set of a single exercise before advancing to the next exercise. You should also rest 1-3 minutes in between sets so that you’re body is fully recovered before you go again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: I recommend 1-1.5 minute rest periods for isolation exercises like curls, and 2-3 minute rest periods for compound movements like squats and bench press (because they require more energy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will allow you to be as strong as possible for every single set of your workout. You will be able to lift more weight for more reps. And, at the end of day, studies show that getting stronger is one of the primary drivers of muscle growth. More strength = more muscle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-carb-up&quot;&gt;2: Carb up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most guys think they need to focus on eating protein if they want to bulk up fast. And yes, protein is important, but carbs are even more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you consume a lot of carbs, you increase the amount of “glycogen” in your muscle cells. And this will give you more energy in the gym. In other words, you will be able to lift more weight for more reps. And remember, getting stronger is the #1 way to force muscle growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What carbs should you eat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my top 5 carb sources for bulking up: potatoes, rice, oats, bread, and pasta. Incorporate large portions of these into all of your meals and you will grow faster than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-use-slow-negatives&quot;&gt;3: Use slow negatives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-img&quot; src=&quot;/jekyll-theme-fitness/images/posts/How to Bulk up Fast/bulk-up-fast-negatives.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way you perform each rep is also very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you just haphazardly sling the weights around the gym, you won’t see any results (but you might injure yourself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, you should lower the weights in a slow and controlled fashion. On one hand, this will force you to check your ego and use a weight that’s not too heavy. On the other hand, studies have shown that the eccentric (or negative) part of the rep plays a large role in muscle growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, I recommend a 2/0/1 tempo (lower the weights for 2 seconds, don’t pause at the bottom, then explode back up in 1 second). This will make sure your form is on point and also help you pack on muscle as fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-try-this-gainer-shake&quot;&gt;4: Try this gainer shake&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fact: consuming enough calories to gain weight is a crucial part of bulking up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you have a busy schedule, it can be challenging to sit down and eat 3 full meals per day… That’s where my gainer shake comes in. I make this for lunch every single day to make sure I get enough calories, carbs, and protein to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Milk (2 cups)
Oats (3/4 cup)
Peanut butter (3 tbsp)
Protein powder (1 scoop)
Creatine (5 grams)
Put all of these into a blender (add ice if you want) and BOOM! Lunch is served.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-cut-the-cardio&quot;&gt;5: Cut the cardio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-img&quot; src=&quot;/jekyll-theme-fitness/images/posts/How to Bulk up Fast/bulk-up-fast-cardio.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said in #4 above, you need to eat enough calories to gain weight if you want to bulk up… so if you’re burning calories like a mad man doing cardio 2-3x per week, then it’s going to be very hard to make gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I recommend only one day of cardio per week while bulking. Any more than this and you will be working directly against your goals. However, it’s still important to do a little cardio (1x per week) in order to maintain heart health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of what type of cardio is best for gaining mass, I recommend low intensity cardio (like running or biking) for about 30 min – 1 hr. Personally, I play pick-up basketball for my cardio, because I quickly get bored if I’m just running or biking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-make-eating-your-job&quot;&gt;6: Make eating your job&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know how to bulk up fast, there’s one simple answer: you need to lift and eat… consistently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot skip meals and rely on small snacks if you’re serious about gaining mass. You need to treat eating like it’s your job. Every morning, you need to consider your schedule for the day and plan time to fit in 3 big meals. This will help prevent situations where you get too busy and “forget” to eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No more excuses, man. One big meal per day is not going to cut it. Man up and start eating big… every single day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How to Bulk up Fast</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Fastest Way to Build Muscle Naturally</title><link href="/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/17/fastest-way-to-build-muscle-naturally.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Fastest Way to Build Muscle Naturally" /><published>2018-11-17T12:16:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-17T12:16:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/17/fastest-way-to-build-muscle-naturally</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/17/fastest-way-to-build-muscle-naturally.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-fastest-way-to-build-muscle-naturally-without-steroids&quot;&gt;The Fastest Way to Build Muscle Naturally (Without Steroids)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-img&quot; src=&quot;/jekyll-theme-fitness/images/posts/The Fastest Way to Build Muscle Naturally/1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building muscle without steroids can be extremely challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The harsh truth is that most fitness models, bodybuilders, and movie stars supplement their training with drugs. And this makes it very easy for them to pack on mass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, anabolic steroids manipulate your hormone levels and interact directly with your muscle cells to increase muscle protein synthesis – and this radically enhances your rates of muscle growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are a lot of negative side effects to taking steroids, from short-term aggression and acne to long-term brain damage and crippled testosterone production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-img&quot; src=&quot;/jekyll-theme-fitness/images/posts/The Fastest Way to Build Muscle Naturally/transformationNew.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-get-lean-before-you-bulk-up&quot;&gt;1: Get Lean BEFORE You Bulk Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-img&quot; src=&quot;/jekyll-theme-fitness/images/posts/The Fastest Way to Build Muscle Naturally/body-fat-hormone-levels-graph.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to cut down and get lean (before you gain weight and bulk up).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While steroids allow you to efficiently pack on mass and shred fat regardless of your body fat percentage, it’s a different story as a natural lifter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Getting Lean Naturally Boosts Testosterone
Studies show that higher levels of body fat are linked with lower levels of testosterone and decreased insulin sensitivity. They also confirm that it’s possible to increase your testosterone (and your insulin sensitivity) simply by lowering your body fat percentage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is significant because both of these things play a large role in the muscle building process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, higher levels of testosterone (and increased insulin sensitivity) both lead to higher rates of muscle protein synthesis. And this means that you get to build more muscle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#2: Once Lean, Gain Weight SLOWLY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-img&quot; src=&quot;/jekyll-theme-fitness/images/posts/The Fastest Way to Build Muscle Naturally/max-muscle-gains-graph.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve reached the aforementioned level of around 12-15% body fat, it’s time to build some muscle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you must be careful here. Traditional bodybuilding-style bulking (where you aim to gain as much as 1-2 pounds per week) only works well for steroid users…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Gaining Weight Too Fast Leads to Fat Gain
As I mentioned above, your body is only naturally capable of synthesizing about half a pound of muscle per week… and that’s only if you’re brand new to lifting! This means that any weight you gain beyond this point will be strictly fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like anything in life, there are diminishing marginal returns. The more training experience you have, and the more muscle you build, the harder it becomes to gain additional mass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With steroids, this limit does not exist. You can stuff your face, gain 1-2 pounds per week, and almost all of it will be muscle. And this is why a lot of bodybuilding advice tells you to “eat big” and gain weight fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you’re a natural lifter, gaining weight too fast will just make you fat!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Fastest Way to Build Muscle Naturally (Without Steroids)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">6 Beginner Exercises to Build Mass Fast</title><link href="/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/17/beginner-exercises.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6 Beginner Exercises to Build Mass Fast" /><published>2018-11-17T12:16:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-17T12:16:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/17/beginner-exercises</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/17/beginner-exercises.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;6-beginner-exercises-to-build-mass-fast&quot;&gt;6 Beginner Exercises to Build Mass Fast&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-img&quot; src=&quot;/jekyll-theme-fitness/images/posts/6 Beginner Exercises to Build Mass Fast/1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-dumbbell-goblet-squat&quot;&gt;1: Dumbbell Goblet Squat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The squat is the most important movement you will ever learn. While it focuses on building strength and mass in the lower body, it will also develop good posture and unparalleled total body power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goblet squat is the easiest form of the squat to learn. This does NOT necessarily mean that it’s easy to do – you can still make it extremely difficult by opting to use a heavy dumbbell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2 main things to focus on when doing this exercise are keeping your feet flat on the floor the entire time and keeping your chest upright (press the top of the dumbbell against your chest to make this effortless).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next Step: Barbell Back Squat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-dumbbell-step-back-lunge&quot;&gt;2: Dumbbell Step Back Lunge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the squat is the most complete lower body movement, it’s a relatively quad-dominant exercise. And so it’s important to balance this out with something that hits the posterior chain a bit harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your posterior chain consists of your lower back, glutes (butt), and hamstrings. A great way to hit the posterior chain for beginners is with the step back lunge. This movement still builds mass in your quads, but it also targets the glutes and hamstrings more than a traditional squat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2 main things to focus on when doing this exercise are keeping your chest upright the entire time and picturing dropping your back knee down to the ground, rather than reaching it backwards behind you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next Step: Dumbbell Bulgarian Split Squat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-weighted-push-up&quot;&gt;3: Weighted Push-Up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important that you master the basic pushing movement before you get into bench presses and the like. And don’t worry – this will still be extremely effective and quickly pack mass onto your pecs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The push-up is the classic pushing exercise. And I’m assuming you can probably bang out a bunch of push-ups no problem… Which is why we’re adding weight to it! Just throw a weighted plate on your back (start with 10 lbs, then 25, then 45) – a backpack with heavy stuff inside will do if you’re working out at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2 main things to focus on when doing this exercise are keeping your back straight (not allowing your butt to sink towards the floor) and using a full range of motion (your t-shirt should make contact with the floor at the bottom on the movement).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next Step: Barbell Bench Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-seated-dumbbell-shoulder-press&quot;&gt;4: Seated Dumbbell Shoulder Press&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s not forget about the deltoids! A big pair of coconut shoulders will make you look like a beast (shirtless and in clothes), so it’s important they get some action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way for beginners to hit their shoulders is with a seated dumbbell shoulder press. This will support your back and allow you to focus fully on working the delts (while getting some solid tricep work in there, too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2 main things to focus on when doing this exercise are making sure your forearms stay completely vertical the entire time (your arms will get closer at the top of the movement) and keeping your back straight and not allowing it to arch as you press the weight up (pushing your butt into the back of the seat will help).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next Step: Barbell Overhead Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-inverted-bodyweight-row&quot;&gt;5: Inverted Bodyweight Row&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time for the back! A lot of new lifters tend to neglect their back and focus more on their chest and arms. This will screw you over in the long term! It will ruin your posture, turn you into a hunchback, and just make you look silly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An amazing movement to target your back is the inverted row. This uses only your bodyweight, but it’s still incredibly challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2 main things to focus on when doing this exercise are keeping your body straight (contracting your ab muscles will help) and driving your elbows back as you raise your body up (you should pinch your shoulder blades together at the top of every rep).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next Step: Barbell Bent Over Row&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-lat-pulldown&quot;&gt;6: Lat Pulldown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright the final exercise we’ll cover is the lat pulldown. When combined with the inverted row, this will build a beastly set of lats, upper back muscles, and biceps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend using an overhand, shoulder-width grip to get started. The traditional wide grip can be strenuous on your rotator cuff and is best avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2 main things to focus on when doing this exercise are driving down through your elbows when pulling the bar down, and using a full range of motion (your arms should be straight at the top of each rep, and the bar should hit your chest at the bottom).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">6 Beginner Exercises to Build Mass Fast</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Build Muscle and Stay Lean 3 Crucial Steps</title><link href="/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/12/how-to-build-muscle-and-stay-lean.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Build Muscle and Stay Lean 3 Crucial Steps" /><published>2018-11-12T15:16:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-12T15:16:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/12/how-to-build-muscle-and-stay-lean</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/12/how-to-build-muscle-and-stay-lean.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-build-muscle-and-stay-lean-3-crucial-steps&quot;&gt;How to Build Muscle and Stay Lean: 3 Crucial Steps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-img&quot; src=&quot;/jekyll-theme-fitness/images/posts/How to Build Muscle and Stay Lean 3 Crucial Steps/1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-eat-the-right-amount-of-calories&quot;&gt;1: Eat the Right Amount of Calories&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fact #1: You can’t build muscle efficiently if you don’t gain weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your body CANNOT synthesize new muscle tissue unless you consume MORE calories than you burn. This means you must eat enough food to gain weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you do this, your body is forced to do something with the extra energy that you’re not burning. It will either store it as fat, or use it to build muscle. In steps 2 and 3 we’ll cover exactly how to make sure that your body uses it to build muscle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fact #2: Your body can only build about 0.5 pounds of new muscle per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As badly as you want to pack on 20 pounds of muscle mass in the next month, your body has a natural. Experts agree that you can only build about half a pound of muscle per week (unless you use steroids).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when you’re new to lifting weights, you might be able to build slightly more than this. But as you get bigger and bigger, the rate at which you can gain more muscle gets slower and slower (as you approach your body’s natural limit). Either way, if you gain weight too quickly, you risk putting on fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means you should aim to gain about 0.5 pounds per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, gaining weight at EXACTLY this pace can be challenging, so I recommend aiming to gain about 1-3 pounds per month. Don’t stress the exact number, as long as you’re putting on a little bit of weight you’ll see quality results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most efficient way to control your weight gain is to count your calories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this sounds like a pain in the ass, but it’s actually quite easy. Just download a simple calorie counting app on your phone like “MyFitnessPal” and use it to track how many calories you’re eating every day. The app will also help you calculate how many calories you need to eat in order to gain weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-get-stronger-in-the-gym&quot;&gt;2: Get Stronger in the Gym&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-img&quot; src=&quot;/jekyll-theme-fitness/images/posts/How to Build Muscle and Stay Lean 3 Crucial Steps/how-to-build-muscle-and-stay-lean-strenght.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fact #1: You must get stronger in order to build new muscle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look – your body will only build new muscle tissue if you give it a reason to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go to the gym every week and lift the same amount of weight for the same amount of reps, then your body has no reason to build new muscle mass… your current muscle is already doing a great job on its own. However, if you lift progressively heavier and heavier weights, then your body will be forced to respond by synthesizing new muscle tissue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because it will NEED additional muscle mass in order to meet these increasing demands! And this is known as the principle of progressive overload.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fact #2: Some exercises are better than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, there are hundreds (if not thousands) of different exercises to choose from. So how do you decide which to focus on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple: use the exercises that allow you to lift the most weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These exercises recruit the most fibers in your muscle tissue and activate the most motor units in your nervous system. And these 2 factors combine to raise your rates of muscle protein synthesis and induce the most muscle growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means you should focus on getting stronger doing compound exercises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compound exercises are exercises that work several large muscle groups at the same time. This allows you to lift the most weight doing these movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Effective compound exercises include: squats, lunges, bench press, dips, pull ups, deadlifts, shoulder press, and rows. These exercises should be the focus of your workouts. And you should be trying to get stronger and lift more weight (or do more reps) each time that you do them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-img&quot; src=&quot;/jekyll-theme-fitness/images/posts/How to Build Muscle and Stay Lean 3 Crucial Steps/how-to-build-muscle-and-stay-lean-rest.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that you need to take days off… and get sufficient sleep!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you lift weights every single day, you’ll actually suppress your levels of muscle protein synthesis and prevent yourself from building new muscle. This is why I recommend doing full body workouts just 3 days per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally you should aim to get 7-8 hours of sleep per night. This will ensure that you aren’t limiting the amount of anabolic hormones your body is naturally releasing. A few tips to improve your quality of sleep include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t look at screens for 1 hour before bed
Keep your room cool (use AC or open windows)
Fully shut your blinds and curtains to darken the room
These simple tweaks can dramatically improve your ability to fall asleep (and actually stay asleep throughout the entire night).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s a wrap! If you follow these 3 steps, I guarantee that you’ll build new muscle mass at an optimal rate… and avoid gaining fat in the process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How to Build Muscle and Stay Lean: 3 Crucial Steps</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First post to config the theme</title><link href="/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/12/first-post-config.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First post to config the theme" /><published>2018-11-12T12:16:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-12T12:16:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/12/first-post-config</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll-theme-fitness/2018/11/12/first-post-config.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;title-level-1&quot;&gt;Title level 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;title-level-2&quot;&gt;Title level 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;title-level-3&quot;&gt;Title level 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;title-level-4&quot;&gt;Title level 4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;title-level-5&quot;&gt;Title level 5&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;title-level-6&quot;&gt;Title level 6&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet consectetur adipisicing elit. Delectus ratione ea ipsa hic. Qui ab, dolorem neque, voluptatem cum quisquam quam incidunt suscipit pariatur assumenda voluptatum natus vitae eligendi iusto?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;title-level-1-1&quot;&gt;Title level 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet consectetur adipisicing elit. Delectus ratione ea ipsa hic. Qui ab, dolorem neque, voluptatem cum quisquam quam incidunt suscipit pariatur assumenda voluptatum natus vitae eligendi iusto?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title-level-2-1&quot;&gt;Title level 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet consectetur adipisicing elit. Delectus ratione ea ipsa hic. Qui ab, dolorem neque, voluptatem cum quisquam quam incidunt suscipit pariatur assumenda voluptatum natus vitae eligendi iusto?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;title-level-3-1&quot;&gt;Title level 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet consectetur adipisicing elit. Delectus ratione ea ipsa hic. Qui ab, dolorem neque, voluptatem cum quisquam quam incidunt suscipit pariatur assumenda voluptatum natus vitae eligendi iusto?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Title level 1 Title level 2 Title level 3 Title level 4 Title level 5 Title level 6 Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet consectetur adipisicing elit. Delectus ratione ea ipsa hic. Qui ab, dolorem neque, voluptatem cum quisquam quam incidunt suscipit pariatur assumenda voluptatum natus vitae eligendi iusto?</summary></entry></feed>